Guide to the James Marshall Osborn Collection of Lady Sydney Morgan
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James Marshall Osborn collection of Lady Sydney Morgan
1803-1859
GEN MSS 1126
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.5
(6 boxes)
Comprised chiefly of letters to Morgan from friends and admirers, including Anne Jane Gore Hamilton, Joseph Atkinson, Charles Babbage, John Bowring, Richard Burgess, Henry Fothergill Chorley, Richard Ford, Catherine Grace Frances Moody Gore, Richard James Lane, Thomas Charles Morgan, Roderick Impey Murchison, Richard Phillips, Cyrus Redding, Marmion W. Savage, Horace Smith, Joseph Cooper Walker, and Thomas Wallace. There are also a few letters from Morgan to other correspondents; letters to Thomas Charles Morgan from friends and colleagues, including many from Cyrus Redding, Horace Smith, and Thomas Wallace; and several third party letters. In addition, there are three boxes of letters sorted by name of sender, and one manuscript copy in an unidentified hand of Lady Sydney Morgan's "The Tabinet Nightcap."
Osborn, James M. (James Marshall), 1906-1976
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn, 1950-1951.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical/Historical note
Lady Sydney Morgan (born Sydney Owenson circa 1778 in Dublin, Ireland) was the daughter of the actor Robert Owenson. She was educated at home and at private schools. After serving as a governess she began a writing career, during which she authored numerous works of fiction, including The Wild Irish Girl (1806). The marchioness of Abercorn made Owenson her lady companion, and through Abercorn met and married Sir Thomas Morgan in 1812. She continued writing novels, verse, and works on politics and society. In 1839 she moved to London, where she enjoyed a rich social life. She died in London in 1859.
Scope and Contents
Comprised chiefly of letters to Morgan from various friends and admirers, including Anne Jane Gore Hamilton, Joseph Atkinson, Charles Babbage, John Bowring, Richard Burgess, Henry Fothergill Chorley, Richard Ford, Catherine Grace Frances Moody Gore, Richard James Lane, Thomas Charles Morgan, Roderick Impey Murchison, Richard Phillips, Cyrus Redding, Marmion W. Savage, Horace Smith, Joseph Cooper Walker, and Thomas Wallace. There are also a few letters from Morgan to various people; letters to Thomas Charles Morgan from friends and colleagues, including many from Cyrus Redding, Horace Smith, and Thomas Wallace; and several third party letters. In addition, there are three boxes of letters sorted by name of sender, and one manuscript copy in an unidentfifed hand of Lady Sydney Morgan's "The Tabinet Nightcap."
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Authors, Irish -- 19th century; Authors -- Ireland -- 19th century; Abercorn, Anne Jane Gore Hamilton, Marchioness of, -1827; Atkinson, Joseph, 1743-1818; Babbage, Charles, 1791-1871; Bowring, John, 1792-1872; Burgess, Richard, 1796-1881; Chorley, Henry Fothergill, 1808-1872; Ford, Richard, 1796-1858; Gore, Mrs. (Catherine Grace Frances), 1799-1861; Lane, Richard James, 1800-1872; Morgan, Lady (Sydney), 1783-1859; Morgan, Thomas Charles, Sir, 1783-1843; Murchison, Roderick Impey, Sir, 1792-1871; Osborn, James M. (James Marshall), 1906-1976; Phillips, R., Sir (Richard), 1767-1840; Redding, Cyrus, 1785-1870; Savage, M. W. (Marmion Wilme), 1804-1872; Smith, Horace, 1779-1849; Walker, Joseph C. (Joseph Cooper), -1810; Wallace, Thomas Wallace, Baron, 1768-1844
- Correspondence
  - Letters from Lady Sydney Morgan
    - AL in the third person to [Richard?] Bentley, [circa 1857] (Box 1)
    - 6 ALS and 1 letter (copied) to her sister, Olivia Lady Clarke, 1808-1819, undated (Box 1)
    - AL (draft) in the third person to [Henry] Colburn, [London], 1838 December 28 (Box 1)
    - AL (incomplete draft) to Sir Malby [Crofton], [London], undated (Box 1)
    - ALS to [William Hepworth] Dixon, [London?], 1857 February 18 (Box 1)
    - ALS to [Mrs. Lewis?], [Dublin], undated (Box 1)
    - ALS to Sir Charles Nicholson, [London], 1859 March 10 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      With envelope; enclosed in a wrapper endorsed in [Sir Charles Nicholson's?] hand; removed from: Sydney Lady Morgan's Passages from My Autobiography (London, 1859).
    - Letter (copied in the hand of Geraldine Jewsbury?) to [Sir C. Omsby?], Anglesey, 1808 May 8 (Box 1)
    - ALS to Mrs. Parker, Dublin, 1835 August 18 (Box 1)
    - AL (incomplete) to an unidentified recipient, [1850?] (Box 1)
  - Letters to Lady Sydney Morgan
    - Abercorn, Anne Jane (Gore) Hamilton, marchioness, d. 1827. 9 ALS to "Glorvina," [Dublin?], 1810-1811, undated (Box 1)
    - Abercorn, John James Hamilton, 1st marquess of, 1756-1818. 6 AL, 1810-1811, undated (Box 1)
    - Ackermann, Rudolph, 1764-1834. ALS, London, 1823 April 21 (Box 1)
    - Albemarle, George Thomas Keppel, 6th earl of, 1799-1891. 2 ALS, [Dublin], 1826 (Box 1)
      Signed George Keppel.
    - Anglesey, Charlotte (Cadogan) Paget, marchioness of, d. 1853. 4 ALS and one invitation (in an unidentified hand), [1831-1833], undated (Box 1)
      Note on verso of [1833?] Jan 23 letter in Lady Morgan's hand.
    - Anglesey, Henry William Paget, 1st marquess of, 1768-1854. 2 ALS, 1829, 1833 (Box 1)
    - Ashe, Thomas, 1770-1835. ALS, Dublin, 1824 August 2 (Box 1)
    - Atkinson, Joseph, 1743-1818. 8 ALS to "Glorvina", 1806-1810 (Box 1)
    - Babbage, Charles, 1792-1871. 14 ANS and AN in the third person, 1837-1854 (Box 1)
    - Bentley, George, 1828-1895. AL and ALS, London, 1859 (Box 1)
    - Bentley, Richard, 1794-1871. 10 ALS, London, 1833-1859 (Box 1)
    - Betham, Sir William, 1779-1853. AL in the third person, Stradbook House, 1834 March 22 (Box 1)
    - Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. 6 ALS, 1822-1823 (Box 1)
    - Burgess, Richard, 1796-1881. 11 ALS, London, 1844-1859 (Box 1)
    - Burgoyne, Sir John Fox, bart., 1782-1871. ALS, [Straburn?], 1838 January 11 (Box 1)
    - Cadogan, George Cadogan, 3d earl of, 1783-1864. ALS, London, 1833 March 26 (Box 1)
    - Carlisle, Sir Anthony, 1768-1848. ALS, [London?], [1824?] (Box 1)
    - Carlisle, George Howard, 6th earl, 1773-1848. 2 ALS, [1842] (Box 1)
    - Carlisle, Georgiana Dorothy (Cavendish) Howard, countess of, d. 1858. 3 ALS, 1837-1842 (Box 1)
    - Chambers, Robert, 1802-71. ALS, Edinburgh, 1855 March 5 (Box 1)
    - Chambers, William Fredrick, 1786-1855. 3 ALS, Lymington, 1843 (Box 1)
    - Chorley, Henry Fothergill, 1808-1872. 9 ALS and ANS, London, 1835-1842 (Box 1)
    - Clanricarde, Ulick John de Burgh, 1st marquess of, 1802-1874. 3 ALS, 1830-1853 (Box 1)
    - Clarendon, George William Frederick Villiers, 4th earl of, 1800-1870. 3 ALS, [Dublin], [1823, 1828] (Box 1)
    - Cockburn, Sir George, 1763-1847. 3 ALS, 1823-1830 (Box 1)
    - Colburn, Henry, d. 1855. Note in third person, [London], [1834?] (Box 1)
    - Constable, Archibald, 1774-1827. 2 AL, Edinburgh, 1816 (Box 1)
    - Constant de Rebecque, Henri Benjamin, 1767-1830. 2 AL, [Paris], 1818, 1819 (Box 1)
    - Cork and Orrery, Mary (Monckton), countess of, 1746-1840. 1 ALS and 5 letters and notes dictated, [London], [1825-1839] (Box 1)
      Letter dated 1839 Jun addressed also to Miss Clarke.
    - Croker, John Wilson, 1780-1857. AL and AN in the third person, 1801, 1817 (Box 1)
    - Cuvier, Georges Leopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert, baron, 1769-1832. AN in the third person from M. and Mme. Cuvier, [Paris], [1819?] (Box 1)
    - Dacre, Babarina (Ogle) Wilmot Brand, Lady, 1768-1854. 3 ALS, London, [1837?] (Box 1)
    - De Dunstanville, Harriet (Lemon) Basset, baroness. ALS, [London], [1850?] (Box 1)
    - Denon, Dominique Vivant, baron, 1747-1825. ALS, Paris, [circa 1818-1819] (Box 1)
    - Devonshire, Lady Elizabeth (Hervey) Foster Cavendish, duchess of, d. 1824. AL in the third person, Paris, [1818 December?] 29 (Box 1)
    - Dilke, Charles Wentworth, 1789-1864. 2 ALS, [1857, 1858?] (Box 1)
    - Dilke, Sir Charles Wentworth, 1810-1869. 3 ALS, 1843-1854 (Box 1)
    - Edgeworth, Richard Lovell, 1744-1817. ALS, Edgeworthstown, 1806 December 23 (Box 1)
    - Ellesmere, Harriet Catherine (Greville) Egerton, countess, 1800-1866. ALS, [Dublin], [1828?] November 25 (Box 1)
    - Elliston, Robert William, 1774-1831. ALS, [London], 1821 December 25 (Box 1)
    - Ensor, George, 1769-1843. ALS, 1826 September 19 (Box 1)
    - Evans, Sir George DeLacy, 1787-1870. 2 ALS, [London?], [1824, 1855?] (Box 1)
    - Fitzgerald, James, 1742-1835. AN in the third person, 1830 November 2 (Box 1)
    - Forbes, Edward, 1815-1854. 4 ALS, [1853-1856] (Box 1)
    - Ford, Richard, 1796-1858. 24 ALS, 1848-1856 (Box 1)
    - Furlong, Thomas, 1794-1827. ALS, [London?], [1820?] March 19 (Box 1)
      Paper watermarked 1820.
    - Gérard, François Pascal, baron, 1770-1837. 3 ALS in French, [Paris], [1819-1837?] (Box 1)
    - Glenelg, Charles Grant, 1st baron, 1778-1866. ALS, Tunbridge Wells, 1820 July 31 (Box 1)
    - Goodhugh, William, 1799?-1842. ALS, [London], 1838 December 29 (Box 1)
    - Gore, Catherine Grace Frances (Moody), 1799-1861. 11 ALS and ANS, [1836-1855] (Box 1)
    - Granville, Augustus Bozzi, 1783-1872. ALS, [London], 1842 May 2 (Box 1)
    - Griffin, Henry, bp. of Limerick. 3 ALS, 1857-1858 (Box 1)
    - Hallam, Henry, 1777-1859. ANS, [London], [1851?] (Box 1)
    - Hardinge, Lady Emily Jane (Stewart) James, viscountess, d. 1865. 14 ALS, [1830-55], undated (Box 1)
    - Hardinge, Henry Hardinge, 1st viscount, 1785-1856. ALS, [London], 1832 July 30 (Box 1)
    - Hawtrey, Edward Craven, 1789-1862. 4 ALS, 1841-1844 (Box 1)
    - Hayward, Abraham, 1801-1884. ALS, [London?], [1846 June 6] (Box 1)
    - Herbert, Sidney Herbert, baron, 1810-1861. ANS, [London], 1846 Jun 9 (Box 1)
    - Holland, Henry Edward Vassel Fox, 4th baron, 1802-1859. ANS, [London], 1851 August 2 (Box 1)
    - Inglis, Henry David, 1795-1835. ALS, [London], 1835 February 12 (Box 1)
    - Jesse, Edward, 1780-1868. ALS, [London?], 1838 June 8 (Box 1)
    - Jewsbury, Geraldine Endsor, 1812-1880. 3 ALS to [Sydney] Lady Morgan, 1854-1858 (Box 1)
    - Jouy, Victor Joseph Étienne de, 1764-1846. 2 ALS in French, [Paris], [1818?, 1819] (Box 1)
    - Kelly, Sir FitzRoy, 1796-1880. ALS, [London], 1854 May 27 (Box 2)
    - King, John. 1788-1847. ALS, Clifton, 1832 July 5 (Box 2)
    - Lamb, Lady Caroline (Ponsonby), 1785-1828. AL in the third person, [London], [1824 May] (Box 2)
    - Lane, Richard James, 1800-1872. 10 ALS, [London?], 1854-1855 (Box 2)
    - Lawless, John, 1773-1837. AL in the third person, [Dublin], 1830 October 8 (Box 2)
    - Layard, Sir Austen Henry. 1817-1894. 2 AN in the third person, 1851, 1854 (Box 2)
    - Leahy, Edward Daniel, 1797-1875. ALS, [London], 1830 September 2 (Box 2)
    - Leigh, Augusta (Byron), 1782-1851. ALS, [London], [1838?] (Box 2)
    - Lockhart, John Gibson, 1794-1854. ALS, [London], [1842?] April 27 (Box 2)
    - Macdonnell, Sir Alexander, bart., 1794-1875. ALS, Dublin, 1849 September 30 (Box 2)
    - Mackenzie, Robert Shelton, 1809-1880. 2 ALS, 1834, 1844 (Box 2)
    - Maclise, Daniel, 1806-1870. AN in third person, [London], [1843?] (Box 2)
    - Macready, William Charles, 1793-1873. ALS, [London], undated (Box 2)
    - Maturin, Charles Robert, 1782-1824. ALS, [1821?] (Box 2)
    - Milman, Henry Hart, 1791-1868. ALS and ANS, [London], [1852, 1853?] (Box 2)
    - Monteagle, Thomas Spring-Rice, 1st baron, 1790-1866. AN in the third person, [London], [1824? January] (Box 2)
    - Moore, Bessie (Dyke). ALS, Chippenham, undated (Box 2)
    - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852. ANS, [Paris], [1829? May 17] (Box 2)
    - Morgan, Sir Thomas Charles, 1783-1843. 16 ALS and 1 letter copied in the hand of Geraldine Jewsbury, [Dublin], [circa 1809-1811] (Box 2)
    - Murchison, Charlotte (Hugonin), lady. 6 ALS, 1855-1859 (Box 2)
    - Murchison, Sir Roderick Impey, bart., 1792-1871. 23 ALS and ANS, 1844-1858 (Box 2)
    - Murray, Sir John, bart., 1768?-1827. ALS, [London], [1824?] July 3 (Box 2)
    - Murray, John, 1778-1843. ALS, [London], 1831 March 12 (Box 2)
    - Napier, Sir William Francis Patrick, 1785-1860. ALS, [London], [1857? October 22] (Box 2)
    - Northumberland, Charlotte-Florentia (Clive) Percy, duchess of, d. 1866. AL in the third person, [Dublin], April 23 (Box 2)
    - Nugent, George Grenville, baron, 1788-1850. 5 ALS, 1836-1850 (Box 2)
    - Owen, Henry Charles Cunliffe, 1821-1867. 5 ALS, 1852-1854 (Box 2)
    - Owen, Robert, 1771-1858. ALS, 1833 May (Box 2)
    - Peel, Sir Robert, bart., 1822-1895. AL in the third person, Drayton Manor, [Warwickshire], 1854 February 12 (Box 2)
    - Percy, Joceline, 1784-1856. ALS, Kingstown, undated (Box 2)
    - Phillips, Sir Richard, 1767-1840. 10 ALS, [London?], 1805-1806 (Box 2)
    - Phipps, Sir Charles Beaumont, 1801-1866. 3 ALS, [London], 1836-1850 (Box 2)
    - Plumptre, Annabella, fl. 1795-1812. ALS, [Dublin?], undated (Box 2)
    - Redding, Cyrus, 1785-1870. 6 ALS, 1828-1832 (Box 2)
      Added to letter of 1831 Nov 29 is a letter to Sir Thomas Charles Morgan.
    - Reeve, Henry, 1813-1895. 2 ALS, [1853?, 1855?] (Box 2)
    - Roscoe, William, 1753-1831. AL in the third person, Liverpool, 1824 August 15 (Box 2)
    - Rowan, Archibald Hamilton, 1751-1834. 3 ALS, [1827], undated (Box 2)
    - St. Albans, Harriet (Mellon) Coutts De Vere, duchess, 1777?-1837. 3 letters in the third person, London (Box 2)
    - St. Albans, William Aubrey De Vere, 9th duke of, 1801-1849. Letter in the third person (dictated?), [London], [1837?] June (Box 2)
    - Savage, Marmion W., 1803-1872. 9 ALS, [Dublin?], [1838-1856] (Box 2)
    - Shee, Sir Martin Archer, 1769-1850. ALS, [London], [1835?] (Box 2)
    - Sheil, Richard Lalor, 1791-1851. 1 AL and 15 ALS, 1828-1847, undated (Box 2)
    - Shelley, Mary (Wollstonecraft), 1797-1851. ALS, [1842?, 1844] (Box 2)
    - Smith, Catherine Amelia (Pybus), d. 1852. 6 ALS and 1 AL in the third person, [London], [1837-1848] (Box 2)
    - Smith, Horatio, 1779-1849. 8 ALS, 1839-1848, undated (Box 2)
    - Spence, Elizabeth Isabella, 1768-1832. ALS, London, undated (Box 2)
    - Stratheden, Mary Elizabeth (Scarlett) Campbell, baroness, d. 1860. 2 ALS, [1845?, 1853?] (Box 2)
    - Stuart, Christina Alexandria Egypta (Bonaparte), Lady Dudley Stuart, d. 1847. 8 ALS in French, [London], [1834-1837?] (Box 2)
    - Talma, François Joseph, 1763-1826. ALS, [Paris], [1818 December 30] (Box 2)
    - Taylor, Tom, 1817-1880. 2 AL, [London?], 1846 (Box 2)
      From the "Author of Sir Roger de Coverley."
    - Tennent, Sir James Emerson, 1804-1869. ALS, [London], [1855] (Box 2)
    - Tennent, Robert James. ALS (first part wanting), Belfast, 1834 May 22 (Box 2)
    - Tighe, Mary (Blachford), 1772-1810. 2 ALS, [circa 1808] (Box 2)
    - Twiss, Horace, 1787-1849. ALS, [London], 1846 September 9 (Box 2)
    - Walker, George, 1772-1847. ALS, London, 1831 March 11 (Box 2)
    - Walker, Joseph Cooper, 1761-1810. 10 ALS, Bray, [Ireland], 1806-1807 (Box 2)
    - Wallace, Thomas Wallace, 1st Baron, 1768-1844. 11 ALS, 1808-1843 (Box 2)
    - Warburton, Bartholomew Eliot George, 1810-1852. 19 ALS, [1843-1853] (Box 2)
    - Warburton, George Drought, 1816-1857. 4 ALS, [London?], [1849-1852] (Box 2)
    - Westmorland, John Fane, 11th Earl of, 1784-1859. ALS and AL, 1819, 1829 (Box 2)
    - Wilkinson, Sir John Gardner, 1797-1875. 4 AL in the third person and 8 ALS, 1838-1856 (Box 2)
    - Williams, Helen Maria, 1762-1827. 3 ALS, Paris, 1822, undated (Box 2)
    - Woulfe, Stephen, 1787-1840. ALS, [1836?] (Box 2)
    - Wyatt, Louisa Henrietta (Sheridan). 10 ALS, 1831-1840 (Box 2)
  - Letters to Thomas Charles Morgan
    - Blaquiere, Eleanor (Dobson) Blaquiere, baroness. ALS, London, January 28 (Box 3)
    - Buckingham, James Silk, 1786-1855. ALS, London, [circa 1825] (Box 3)
      Paper watermarked 1825.
    - Burgoyne, Sir John Fox, bart., 1782-1871. ALS, London, 1838 September 4 (Box 3)
    - Carlisle, Sir Anthony, 1768-1848. 3 ALS, London, 1822, 1834, undated (Box 3)
    - Chambers, William Frederick, 1786-1855. ALS, [London], 1842 December 7 (Box 3)
    - Chorley, Henry Fothergill, 1808-1872. 3 ALS, London, 1836-1837 (Box 3)
    - Cloncurry, Valentine Browne Lawless, 2nd baron, 1773-1853. ALS, undated (Box 3)
    - Cockburn, Sir George, 1763-1847. 2 ALS, 1817 (Box 3)
    - Doherty, John, 1783-1850. ALS, [London?], [1830?] August 13 (Box 3)
    - Dunsany, Edward Wadding Plunkett, baron, 1773-1848. ALS, [Dunshaughlin], 1826 February 12 (Box 3)
    - Easthope, Sir John, bart., 1784-1865. ALS, London, 1835 January 22 (Box 3)
      Attached to the letter is a note of identification written in [Geraldine Jewsbury's?] hand.
    - Evans, Sir George DeLacy, 1787-1870. 3 ALS, [circa 1822-1832] (Box 3)
    - Gérard, François Pascal, baron, 1770-1837. AN in the third person, [Paris?], [1829?] June 8 (Box 3)
    - Hardinge, Henry Hardinge, 1st viscount, 1785-1856. 2 AL in the third person, [London], 1830 (Box 3)
    - Howard, Edward, d. 1841. ALS, [London], 1834 March 24 (Box 3)
    - Lawless, John, 1773-1837. 2 ALS, 1823, 1830 (Box 3)
    - Leinster, Augustus Frederick FitzGerald, 3d duke of, 1791-1874. 1 ALS, 1 AN and 1 letter (in an unidentified hand), Carton, 1826-1830 (Box 3)
    - Lucan, George Charles Bingham, 3d earl of, 1800-1888. AN in the third person, Castlebar, 1844 November 2 (Box 3)
    - Macdonnell, Sir Alexander, bart., 1794-1875. 2 ALS, [Dublin], [1836, 1837] (Box 3)
    - Marryat, Frederick, 1792-1848. ALS, [London], [1834?] (Box 3)
    - Maturin, Charles Robert, 1782-1824. 2 ALS, [London], 1821 (Box 3)
    - Maturin, Henrietta (Kingsbury). AL in the third person, [London?], [1831?] November 27 (Box 3)
    - Monteagle, Thomas Spring-Rice, 1st baron, 1790-1866. 2 ANS, 1826, undated (Box 3)
    - Redding, Cyrus, 1785-1870. 33 ALS, 1824-1835 (Box 3)
    - Richardson, George Fleming, 1796?-1848. ALS, [London], 1842 June 3 (Box 3)
    - Richmond, Charles Gordon Lennox, 5th duke of, 1791-1860. ALS, [London], 1828 October 5 (Box 3)
    - Rowan, Archibald Hamilton, 1751-1834. 3 ALS, 1821, 1829, undated (Box 3)
    - Savage, Marmion W., 1803-1872. 6 ALS, [Dublin?], 1842-1843 (Box 3)
    - Sheil, Richard Lalor, 1791-1851. 3 ALS, [Dublin?], 1829-1831 (Box 3)
    - Smith, Horation, 1779-1849. 12 ALS, 1838-1843 (Box 3)
    - Wallace, Thomas Wallace, 1st Baron, 1768-1844. 33 ALS, 1832-1835, undated (Box 3)
    - Third party letters
      - Ford, Richard, 1796-1858. ALS to [Sir William] Stirling[-Maxwell], Brighton, 1848 January 11 (Box 3)
        Originally enclosed in letter from Ford to Lady Morgan, dated 1848 Jan 11.
      - Jones, Sidney J. ALS to Sir Charles [Nicholson], [London], 1859 August 9 (Box 3)
        About the death of her aunt, Sydney Lady Morgan. Enclosed in a wrapper endorsed by Sir Charles Nicholson[?]. Removed from: Passages from My Autobiography by Sydney Lady Morgan (London, 1859).
      - Mornington, William Wellesley-Pole, 3rd earl of, 1763-1845. ANS to an unidentified recipient, Boulogne, 1844 September 20 (Box 3)
        Concerning a present of game for Sydney Lady Morgan.
      - St. Albans, Harriet (Mellon) Coutts De Vere, duchess, 1777?-1837. AL in the third person to [Harriet Charlotte Beaujolois Campbell] Lady Charleville, [London], 1833 July 30 (Box 3)
      - Walker, Joseph Cooper, 1761-1810. ALS to [Joseph?] Atkinson, 1808 November 11 (Box 3)
        Relating to Sydney Owenson, later Lady Morgan.
    - Correspondence sorted by last name of sender
      - "A", 1810-1859 (Box 4)
      - "B", 1809-1859; 2 (Box 4)
      - "C", 1803-1858; 2 (Box 4)
      - "D", 1814-1855 (Box 4)
      - "E", 1818-1840 (Box 4)
      - "F", 1822-1853 (Box 5)
      - "G", 1818-1856 (Box 5)
      - "H", 1824-1856 (Box 5)
      - "I-J", 1818-1853 (Box 5)
      - "K", 1816-1851 (Box 5)
      - "L", 1816-1859 (Box 5)
      - "M", 1814-1856; 2 (Box 5)
      - "N", 1804-1849 (Box 5)
      - "O", 1832-1841 (Box 6)
      - "P", 1819-1855 (Box 6)
      - "Q-R", 1818-1856 (Box 6)
      - "S", 1818-1859 (Box 6)
      - "T", 1818-1859 (Box 6)
      - "U-V", 1828-1850 (Box 6)
      - "W", 1816-1859 (Box 6)
      - "X-Z", 1834-1849 (Box 6)
    - Unsorted letters, [1817-1859]; 5 (Box 6)
- "The Tabinet Nightcap," manuscript copy in an unidentified hand of 72 lines of a work by Lady Sydney Morgan, undated (Box 6)